## Xiaojing Deng

Phone: 216-534-3362 | Email: 8redfishcreative@gmail.com LinkedIn: https://www.linkedin.com/in/xiaojing-deng-b04160248

GitHub: <a href="https://github.com/xiaojing168">https://github.com/xiaojing168</a>jmg168</a>
Portfolio: <a href="https://xiaojing-deng.herokuapp.com">https://xiaojing-deng.herokuapp.com</a>

## **Summary**

Full Stack Web Developer with a 10-year background in graphic design and e-commerce. Effective in combining design principles and problem-solving with a desire to deliver user-friendly applications and software. Proficiency in using the MERN Stack. Recently earned a Certificate in Full Stack Flex Web Development from Case Western Reserve University.

### **Technical Skills**

Back-end Tech: Restful APIs, GraphQL, MongoDB (Mongoose ODM), MySQL (Sequelize),

Express, Node.js, PHP

Front-end Tech: Handlebars.js, React, HTML, JavaScript, Bootstrap, CSS, Sass

Stack: MERN Stack, WordPress

**Applications:** MongoDB, Atlas, GraphQL **Graphic Design:** Figma, Photoshop

# **Work Experience**

#### **8 RED FISH CREATIVE, CO-OWNER**

Lakewood, Ohio. October 2013 – Present

- Actively manage two online Etsy stores as part of a two-person partnership.
- Print and fulfill orders for a yearly average of 600+ buyers.
- Using hand-painted items, Adobe Photoshop & Illustrator, developed a watercolor-design kit for the graphic design/digital creative community.

#### **NENG JING WEB SERVICES, LTC OWNER**

Shenzhen, China. June 2003 – November 2008

- As owner, specialized in web-based solutions for 500 Shenzhen businesses.
- Managed a staff of 10-15 employees including 4 web designers.

### **Education**

Full Stack Flex Web Development Boot Camp Certificate: Case Western Reserve University, Cleveland, Ohio. August 2022 – February 2023

**Associate degree in Accounting:** Wuhan University of Finance and Economics, Wuhan, China. September 1997 – July 2000

# **Projects**

**8 Red Fish Creative** | <a href="https://github.com/xiaojing168jmg168/8-red-fish-creative">https://github.com/xiaojing168jmg168/8-red-fish-creative</a> | <a href="https://eight-red-fish-creative.onrender.com">https://eight-red-fish-creative</a> | <a href="https://eight-red-fish-creative.onrender.com">https://eight-red-fish-creative.onrender.com</a> | <a href="https://eight-red-fish-creative.onrender.com">https:/

- 8 Red Fish Creative is an E-commerce app built from the ground up. Implemented
  features such as user authentication, product listing, search, shopping cart, and checkout
  using Stripe/PayPal payment gateway.
- Core responsibilities: A fully functioning website using MERN stack.
- Technologies: React, Context, Node, Express, MongoDB, Mongoose.

Cars-R-Us | https://github.com/xiaojing168jmg168/cars-r-us | https://floating-river-45182.herokuapp.com

- Cars-R-Us is a website that allows users to advertise information about a car they wish to sell and provide ways for buyers to contact them about the car.
- **Core responsibilities:** Front-end. Built responsive, interactive web pages using Handlebars.js, CSS, and JavaScript. Enhanced user experience with CSS animations.
- **Technologies:** Handlebars.js, Express, Node, MySQL(Sequelize), Bcrypt and Bootstrap.

**Tech Blog |** <u>https://github.com/xiaojing168jmg168/tech-blog-mvc | </u><u>https://tech-blog-xiaojing.herokuapp.com</u>

- A Tech Blog that allows users to login and sign up to create new posts. Posts are editable and can be deleted by the author. Logged-in users can leave comments.
- Core responsibilities: Design, develop, and deploy a fully functioning blog-oriented website.
- Technologies: Model View Controller (MVC), MySQL2, Express, Sequelize, Handlebars and dotenv.